Laubach Literacy International Records
Laubach Literacy International Records
- Caswell, Robert F.
  - Programs International
    - Mexico - General
      - Primers. Schrock, Mary Ellen. Descriptive Analysis of the Adult Literacy Primer "Leamos y Escribamos., 1973 (Box 356)
    - Reports
      - [General], 1965-1974; 6 folders (Box 357)
      - Afghanistan, 1964 (Box 357)
      - Afghanistan, International Afghan Mission, 1970-1971 (Box 357)
      - Afro-Lit, circa 1968 (Box 357)
      - Brazil, 1972-1973 (Box 357)
      - Brazil; Samuelson, Alta, 1967-1968 (Box 357)
      - Colombia, 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box 357)
      - Colombia, 1971-1973; 3 folders (Box 358)
      - Colombia, Medellin, May 1968 (Box 358)
      - Ecuador, 1962; 1968 (Box 358)
      - India, Bengal, 1968-1969 (Box 358)
      - India, Calcutta, Bengal Social Service League, circa 1968 (Box 358)
      - India, Karthicappally, 1972 (Box 358)
      - Israel/Jordan, Ramallah, 1967-1968 (Box 358)
      - Kenya, 1968 (Box 358)
      - Rhodesia, University College of Rhodesia, 1971-1973 (Box 358)
      - South Africa, miscellaneous, 1970-1971 (Box 358)
      - Statistical, 1967-1973; 3 folders (Box 358)
      - Trips, 1968 (Box 358)
      - Trips, Colombia, 1972 (Box 358)
  - Proposals
    - [General], 1961-1971; 3 folders (Box 359)
    - International, 1973 (Box 359)
  - Public Information and Policy (PIP), 1973-1975 (Box 359)
  - Publishing Committee, 1971-1976 (Box 359)
  - Research Development, 1965-1969 (Box 359)
  - Right to Read, 1975 (Box 359)
  - Staff Meetings, 1973 (Box 359)
  - Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages (TESOL), 1967-1974 (Box 359)
  - Testing (Box 359)
  - Trustees, Board of
    - [General], 1971-1975 (Box 359)
    - Longdon, Major A., 1973-1974 (Box 359)
    - Meetings, May 1970-Jan. 1973; 5 folders (Box 359)
    - Meetings, Jan. 1974-May 1975; 4 folders (Box 360)
    - Reports, 1967 (Box 360)
  - Tutoring (Mag. 706); Ferry, Catherine, 1972; 2 folders (Box 360)
  - UNESCO
    - International Volunteer Service, 1967-1972 (Box 360)
    - International Education Year (IEY), 1970 (Box 360)
    - Workshops, 1964-1969 (Box 360)
  - The Unwitting Behavior Modifier / Broughton, Sam, 1975 (Box 360)
  - Vocational Training, 1970 (Box 361)
  - Volunteer Programs and Appeals, 1974 (Box 361)
  - Vowels Have a Code, Riedel, Angela, 1975 (Box 361)
  - World Education Inc., 1966-1971 (Box 361)
  - World Education information file, 1968 (Box 361)
  - World Education reports, 1971 (Box 361)
  - Writers Manual, 3 folders (Box 361)
  - Writers Manual (2nd edition) (Box 361)
  - Writers Manual, The Book: Preparing It, Printing It, Publishing It (Box 361)
  - Writers Manual, Manual de Producion de Libros (Spanish) (Box 361)
  - Writers Manual, On Writing the Manuscript (Box 361)
- Gipson, Priscilla
  - General Files
    - Building Your Language Power, 1969 (Box 362)
    - English for Speakers of Other Languages (ESOL), 1977-1979; 2 folders (Box 362)
    - ESOL, Objectives, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 362)
    - ESOL Trainers Handbook, English for Speakers of Other Languages., 1978 (Box 362)
    - English the New Way, 1969-1971
    - Laubach National Survey of Literacy Teacher Opinion, 1966; 2 folders (Box 362)
    - Literacy: the Issue of the 80's" Laubach Literacy Action, Northeast Conference, June 16-18, 1983 (Box 362)
  - National Affiliation for Literacy Advance (NALA)
    - Awards and certificates (Box 363)
    - Basic Literacy Tutor Workshop, 1980? (Box 363)
    - Certification and Training, 1976 (Box 363)
    - Constitution and bylaws, 1976 (Box 363)
    - English to Speakers of Other Languages (ESOL), 1976 (Box 363)
    - Executive Committee
      - [General], 1976 (Box 363)
      - Handbook, 1976 (Box 363)
      - Meetings, 1975-1976; 4 folders (Box 363)
    - Field Survey
      - Bakersfield, California, Nov. 11-29, 1975 (Box 363)
      - Fort Wayne, Indiana, Oct. 5-16, 1975 (Box 363)
      - Newport News, Virginia (Peninsula), Oct. 24-Nov. 6, 1975 (Box 363)
      - Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, Jan. 23-29, 1977 (Box 363)
      - Orlando, Florida, Nov. 14-19, 1976 (Box 364)
      - St. Louis, Missouri, Oct. 25-29, 1976 (Box 364)
    - Finance, 1976 (Box 364)
    - Guide to Organizing School Tutorial Programs, 1979 (Box 364)
    - How to Start a Volunteer Literacy Project, 1972 (Box 364)
    - International Representatives Kit, 1975 (Box 364)
    - Laubach Way to English/English Speakers of Other Languages (LWE/ESOL), 1976 (Box 364)
    - LWE/ESOL Training
      - Chester, Pennsylvania, Nov. 19-20, 1976 (Box 364)
      - Chicago, Illinois, Oct. 21-23, 1976 (Box 364)
      - Columbia, South Carolina, Sept. 23-25, 1976 (Box 364)
      - Seattle, Washington, Oct. 28-30, 1976 (Box 364)
      - Tucson, Arizona, Jan. 13-15, 1977 (Box 364)
    - LWE Supplement to the ESOL Trainers Handbook, 1978 (Box 364)
    - Laubach Way to English" Trainer Script, 1978 (Box 364)
    - Libraries and Literacy, 1976 (Box 364)
    - Long Range Planning, 1980 (Box 365)
    - Meetings on Goals and Budget, Feb. 13-14, 1975 (Box 365)
    - Meetings on National Conference, June 25-30, 1976 (Box 365)
    - Metro Project, Tutor Trainer Handbook, circa 1974; 1975 (Box 365)
    - Northwest Regional Conference, 1981 (Box 365)
    - Peer Teaching (Box 365)
    - Prison, ABE, 1974 (Box 365)
    - Public Relations Committee, Kit, 1981 (Box 365)
    - Publications, 1975-1976 (Box 365)
    - Reader's Digest article, responses, 1977 (Box 365)
    - Regions, general, 1976-1977 (Box 365)
    - Right to Read (R2R) (Box 365)
    - Schools Tutorial Project (Newland), 1975-1977 (Box 365)
    - Southeast Regional Conference, 1981 (Box 365)
    - Special Education, 1971-1972 (Box 365)
    - Speeches, Position Paper on Teaching English as a Second Language, 1968 (Box 365)
    - State Organizations, 1975 (Box 365)
    - Stauffer, John / "The NALA Study, 1973 (Box 365)
    - Student Interviews, 1970 (Box 366)
    - Tutor Questionnaire, 1970 (Box 367)
  - Newsletters, ESOL Exchange, 1981 (Box 365)
- Koinonia
  - Reports, financial, 1979-1973 (Box 368)
  - Koinonia Magazine, Dec. 1959 (Box 368)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1971-1974; meeting (Box 368)
- Laubach, Effa S.
  - Death notices, 1973 (Box 368)
  - [Miscellaneous], 1980 (Box 448)
- Laubach, Frank C.
  - [General], 1961; 1967-1968 (Box 448)
  - Articles, atomic bomb, 1946-1969 (Box 368)
    See also Memorabilia: Frank C. Laubach: Atomic bomb newspaper articles, 1947-1969 (Box 429).
  - Awards and certificates (Box 458)
  - Bibliographies, 1960 (Box 368)
  - Biographical information (Box 368)
  - Biographical Information, "Each One Teach One" / Marti Dobesh & Maria Houghton (Box 368)
  - Birthdays, 1963-1969 (Box 368)
  - California trips, 1958-1964; 4 folders (Box 448)
  - Correspondence
    - [General], 1952-1966 (Box 368)
    - [General], 1953-1970 (Box 368)
    - Christian Save Your World, 1970 (Box 368)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight David, 1953-1964; photocopies from Eisenhower Library, Abilene, Kansas (Box 368)
    - Griffin, George, 1967 (Box 368)
  - Death Notices
    - [General], 1970 (Box 369)
    - [General], 1970 (Box 448)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 369)
    - Newspaper, June 1970 (Box 369)
  - 80th birthday celebration, 1965 (Box 448)
  - Hollywood Bowl speech, Apr. 1961 (Box 448)
  - How to Teach One and Win One for Christ, 1964 (Box 448)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1965 (Box 448)
  - Miscellaneous ledger book, background information for literacy, 1958 (Box 369)
  - Miscellaneous programs, promotional articles (Box 369)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1955-1979; 300+ articles in individual folders (Box 456)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1950 (Box 458)
  - Newspaper clippings; bibliography, 1971 (Box 369)
  - Nobel Peace Prize nominations, 1964-1969 (Box 369)
  - Philippines, 1932-1937 (Box 458)
  - Promotional material, 1966-1970 (Box 369)
  - Public relations, 1969 (Box 369)
  - Speeches, Chautauqua, 1961 (Box 369)
  - Story of Jesus translations, index cards (Box 448)
  - World Tour, letters from abroad, 1956 (Box 448)
  - Writings
    - Articles and Speeches, 1969 (Box 369)
    - Christ Liveth in Me, 1970; manuscript (Box 369)
    - A Christian Answer to the Atomic Bomb., 194? (Box 369)
    - Christian, Save Your World. (Box 369)
    - The Game With Numbers," rewritten for New Readers / Lili Stevenson, 1961 (Box 369)
    - Going Forward.", 1960 (Box 370)
    - How Each One Can Teach One and Win One For Christ., circa 1964 (Box 370)
    - Learning the Vocabulary of God, A Spiritual Diary., 1956 (Box 370)
    - Making Everybody's World Safe. (Box 370)
    - The Moti-Maya Series: "Stories: A Third Reader for New Literates. (Box 370)
    - A Phonetic Code Used in Hong Kong for Teaching English., 1968 (Box 370)
    - Phonetic Spelling, 1969-1970 (Box 370)
    - The Positive Thing. (Box 370)
    - The Story of Jesus, 1957-1967; draft and various editions; 2 folders (Box 370)
    - Streamlined English. (Box 370)
    - Thirty Years With the Silent Billion., 1960; Chapters 1-5 (Box 370)
    - Thirty Years With the Silent Billion., 1960; Chapters 6-39; 3 folders (Box 371)
    - We Cuud Havv Guud Spelling.", undated (Box 371)
    - We...the People Can Win the Peace," "What Jesus Says About Wealth," and "What Jesus Had to Say About Money, 1945; 1964,; 1966 (Box 371)
  - You Are My Friends, 1968 (Box 448)
- Laubach, Robert S.
  - Afro-Lit, 1967-1968 (Box 371)
  - Afro-Lit meetings, July 19-31, 1970 (Box 371)
  - Arizona, Phoenix and Sun City, Oct. 10-15, 1985 (Box 448)
  - Biographical, circa 1957-1962 (Box 371)
  - California trip, 1971 (Box 371)
  - Correspondence
    - [General], 1957-1974; 4 folders (Box 371)
    - [General], 1968 (Box 448)
    - [General], 1971 (Box 372)
    - [General], Jan.-Aug. 1971; 10 folders (Box 372)
    - [General], Sept. 1971-Nov. 1972; 16 folders (Box 373)
    - [General], Dec. 1972-Dec. 1974; 15 folders (Box 374)
    - [General], Jan. 1975-Mar. 1975; 15 folders (Box 375)
    - [General], Apr.-June 1975; July-Sept. 1976; 6 folders (Box 376)
    - [General], Jan-Jul. 1976; 2 folders (Box 448)
    - [General], Aug.-Dec. 1976; 2 folders (Box 449)
    - [General], Oct.-Dec. 1976/Nov.-Dec. 1977; 7 folders (Box 377)
    - [General], 1978-1979 (Box 377)
    - Afro-lit, 1971-1973 (Box 378)
    - Archival acquisitions, 1972-1974 (Box 378)
    - Assistantships
      - [General], 1971 (Box 378)
      - Adirvu, Adamu, 1971 (Box 378)
      - Baker, Barbara, 1972 (Box 378)
      - Brubecker, J. Allen, 1971 (Box 378)
      - Cooney, Thomas W., 1971 (Box 378)
      - Guillermo, Artemio, 1971-1972 (Box 378)
      - Hillmer, Walter K., 1970-1971 (Box 378)
      - Hoover, Richard, 1971-1972 (Box 378)
      - Kroman, David A., 1971 (Box 378)
      - McFadden, Margaret, 1971 (Box 378)
      - Moir, John, 1971-1972 (Box 378)
      - Roe, Earl, 1970-1971 (Box 378)
      - Rogers, Bob G., 1971 (Box 378)
      - Shipstone, Nora, 1971 (Box 378)
      - Tucker, Bert O., 1971 (Box 378)
      - Vamvakis, Steven N., 1972 (Box 378)
      - Van Delinder, Martha, 1971 (Box 378)
      - Wilcox, William, 1971 (Box 378)
    - California Literacy, 1972 (Box 378)
    - Charles D. Martin Memorial Fund, 1970 (Box 378)
    - Chmaj, Deborah Rinehart, 1973-1974 (Box 378)
    - Christmas Appeal, 1971 (Box 378)
    - Clark, Roberta B., 1971-1972 (Box 378)
    - Clark, Wesley C., 1971 (Box 379)
    - Clark Foundation, See Grants, Clark Foundation.
    - Clickquennoi, Georgia, 1976 (Box 379)
    - Drake Skill, 1971-1972 (Box 379)
    - Foundations, 1971-1974 (Box 379)
    - Fund raising, undated (Box 379)
    - Glorietta Conference, 1971 (Box 379)
    - Grants, Clark Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 379)
    - Harvey, Joan, 1976 (Box 379)
    - IBM World Trade Corporation, 1971-1972 (Box 379)
    - Interim Committee, 1968 (Box 379)
    - Jakes, Cynthia, 1973 (Box 379)
    - Johnson, Eugenia; Vietnam, 1972-1974 (Box 379)
    - Kimberly-Clark Corporation, 1971 (Box 379)
    - Koinonia, 1971-1974 (Box 379)
    - Kwiatkowski, Lorraine, 1972-1973 (Box 379)
    - Lewis, Frank, 1972-1973 (Box 379)
    - Libby, Richard, 1975 (Box 379)
    - Literacy pins, 1967-1968 (Box 379)
    - Magney, Gordon and Grace, 1968-1974 (Box 379)
    - Magsanoc, Maria, 1972 (Box 379)
    - Memorial Fund, Frank C. Laubach, Sept. 20, 1971 (Box 379)
    - Memorial Fund, Frank C. Laubach, Class of 1909, 1971 (Box 379)
    - Memos, Jan.-Mar. 1970 (Box 379)
    - Memos, Apr. 1970-Dec. 1974; 13 folders (Box 380)
    - Minnesota Proposal (Right to Read), 1973 (Box 381)
    - Newton, Carl, 1971 (Box 381)
    - Nigeria, 1973 (Box 381)
    - Oregon Literacy, 1971-1972 (Box 381)
    - Outgoing
      - [General], Jan.-Mar. 1968/Oct.-Dec. 1969; 8 folders (Box 381)
      - [General], 1970-1971; 14 folders (Box 382)
      - Memos, 1972 (Box 383)
      - [General], Jan. 1972-Aug. 1973; 20 folders (Box 383)
      - [General], Sept. 1973-Sept. 1975; 23 folders (Box 384)
      - [General], Nov. 1975/July-Dec. 1977; 4 folders (Box 385)
    - Pfizer, Puerto Rico, 1974 (Box 385)
    - Pitts, Edward, 1973 (Box 385)
    - Raines, Nancy Elizabeth, 1972 (Box 385)
    - Reader's Digest, 1976-1977
    - Rockefeller Foundation Humanities Fellowships, 1976 (Box 385)
    - Roderick, Mrs. R. C., 1971-1974 (Box 385)
    - Rosamond Gifford Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 385)
    - San Miguel, Rachel (Box 385)
    - Schoephoerster, Dr. Hugh / "Shakopee Model., 1974 (Box 385)
    - Stanmore Missionary Press, 1972 (Box 385)
    - Stone Foundation, 1971 (Box 385)
    - Stein, Wendy, 1971 (Box 385)
    - Swann, Mrs. Doris (Box 385)
    - Trip, Missouri, 1972 (Box 386)
    - Trustees, Board of
      - Carruth, Thomas A., 1969-1970 (Box 386)
      - Caudell, Dr. R. Paul, 1967-1971 (Box 386)
      - Charters, Alexander, 1966-1970 (Box 386)
      - Cook, David C. III, 1969-1970 (Box 386)
      - DeMoss, Arthur S., 1968-1970 (Box 386)
      - Hess, Doris, 1971-1975 (Box 386)
      - Mohr, Sidney, 1973-1976 (Box 386)
      - Root, Dr. Robert, 1965-1970 (Box 386)
      - Scholfield, Ethel, 1968-1970 (Box 386)
      - Wilson, George M., 1968-1970 (Box 386)
    - UNESCO, 1966-1970 (Box 386)
    - University United Methodist Church, Mission Study, 1973 (Box 386)
    - Visual Data Corporation, 1969 (Box 386)
    - Volunteer Information Service to America (VISTA), 1968 (Box 386)
    - Volunteers for International Technical Assistance Inc (VITA), 1967-1969 (Box 386)
    - Wasylenko, Lydia, 1974 (Box 386)
    - Watson, Willie Mae, 1964-1968 (Box 386)
    - Whitington, Richard C., 1969 (Box 386)
    - Wiesner, Peter; S.A.L.E.M. Cable T.V, 1974 (Box 386)
    - Wisconsin Literacy Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 386)
    - Wolde, Menbere, 1971-1974 (Box 386)
    - World Association for Christian Communications, 1975 (Box 386)
    - World Education, 1969-1970 (Box 386)
    - World Literature Campaign, 1968-1970 (Box 386)
    - World Vision, 1967-1970 (Box 386)
    - Writer's Workshop, Jan. 12-16, 1970 (Box 386)
    - Youngsphoto Productions, 1968 (Box 386)
  - Editorial Committee, 1975-1977; 2 folders (Box 387)
  - Laubach family, 1971-1977 (Box 387)
  - Literacy journalism papers
    - Adamson, Myra / Missionary Tidings: A Study of a Mission Magazine (Box 388)
    - Adamson, Myra / Reading lessons in Kinyarwanda, 1968 (Box 449)
    - Albright, Jim / The Statue: A Short Story For New Literates (Box 388)
    - Aswandi, Mrs., Mr. Kencke & Mr. Ramdas/ What You Should Know About Printing & Publishing (Box 388)
    - Baker, Dorothy / Techniques employed by Dr. Frank Laubach in teaching the illiterate to read and write, 1956 (Box 449)
    - Beachy, Bertha / A Literacy Program for Somali Women in Mogadiscion Somalia (Box 388)
    - Berg, Paul Conrad / Literacy in the Modern World (Box 388)
    - Benson, Jay E. / Writing For New Literates (Box 388)
    - Bontrager, Robert / Funding Programs of Adult Literacy (Box 388)
    - Brown, Thomas S. / India Mini-Fair U.S. Information Service (Box 388)
    - Bryan, Robert
      - A Ladder of Literacy for Ivory Coast (Box 388)
      - Cagayan Church of Christ Golden Anniversary Yearbook (Box 388)
    - Can you write for the underpriviliged? (Box 449)
    - Case, Ellen / A Study of Laubach Literacy in Alaska (Box 388)
    - Caswell, Robert Conscientizacao
      - Political & Social Awareness (Box 388)
      - Laubach Approach To Literacy (Box 388)
      - LL-NALA in Practice (Box 388)
      - A Plan for the Development...Adult Illiterates in Colombia, South America (Box 388)
      - Evaluation of a Literacy Program (Box 388)
    - Chamberlin, Ralph / A Machine to Teach Reading (Box 388)
    - Community development, 1954 (Box 449)
    - Course Outlines
      - Techniques of Adult Literacy (Box 388)
      - Writing for New Literates (Box 388)
    - Davis, Arthur M. / Journalism Courses in Church Related Colleges (Box 389)
    - Demissew, Taye
      - The Education Corps of Iran (Box 389)
      - Literacy in Ethiopia Historical Study (Box 389)
    - Ellison, Judith / Ladder of Literacy for NYS Migrant Population (Box 389)
    - Ellison, Judith A. / Preparation and evaluation of a sample of ethnic oriented material for adult new readers, 1974 (Box 449)
    - Erskine, Tom / Brazil, Forgotten Giant (Literacy in Brazil) (Box 389)
    - Eshenaur, Ruth / Preparation of curricula for the teaching of literacy missions on the college level, 1966 (Box 449)
    - Eshenaur, Ruth M. / The Relation of Psychology of Learning Theory to Literacy Teaching (Box 389)
    - Family; Beudingen diary (Germany), July 1989 (Box 449)
    - Fausy, Verna, Paul Meyerink, May Lou Santillan / How to Use the Library (Box 389)
    - Froemming, Paul / A Ladder of Literacy for Antigua (Box 389)
    - Gardner, Nancy / Literacy: Cultivator of Rural Development (Box 389)
    - Gatto, Micheline Del / Teaching English to Spanish Speaking People in Greater New York (Box 389)
    - Gipson, Priscilla / Laubach Literacy in the United States (Box 389)
    - Goodman, Vickie / Ladder of Literacy for the Bantu of South Africa (Box 389)
    - Graf, William G. / Outline: Illiteracy Among the Elderly in America (Box 389)
    - Gratix, Carol / Suggestions for a Primer in English: the Method of Sarah Gudschinsky (Box 389)
    - Gridley, Nancy C. / The Intelligent Illiterate (Box 389)
    - Haase, Mary Mallery / John Dewey's Philosophy of Speech Communication as Transaction (Box 389)
    - Hamilton, Beverly
      - The Role of Nationalism in Literacy Campaigns (Box 390)
      - A Ladder of Literacy for Jamaica (Box 390)
    - Hansen, Bonnie / Ladder of Literacy Cleveland, Ohio (Box 390)
    - Hanson, John Hne / Literacy in West Africa (Box 390)
    - Hart, Leslie / Tutoring Log, January 1971 (Box 390)
    - Hayes, Larry / Philanthropy U.S.A (Box 390)
    - Jackson, Miles M.
      - Proposal for a Study of Alienation and Mass Media Behavior Among Blacks in Washington, D.C (Box 390)
      - Washington, D.C.: Some Demographic Factors (Box 390)
    - Jakes, Cynthia L. / Illiteracy: Its Effects on the Illiterate and Society in the U.S (Box 390)
    - Janek, Lothar / A Literacy Program for Unskilled Readers in Germany (Box 390)
    - Johnson, Carl / Research Proposal Reading Levels of the Deaf (Box 390)
    - Johnston, Eugenia / A Ladder of Literacy for the Bru of South Viet Nam (Box 390)
    - Kalang Kadi (Box 449)
    - Koschnick, Kay / Tutoring Log From Learn English the New Way: A Journal of Teaching Experiences (Box 390)
    - Koshy, T.
      - Bibliography: Religious Journalism Papers on File, School of Journalism (Box 391)
      - The Role of Private and Government Programs of India (Box 391)
      - Ladder of Literacy Syracuse, New York (Box 391)
      - Expressed Needs of Functional Illiterates for Materials in Social Studies (Box 391)
    - LaMoreaux, James W. & Gerald V. Stone / Is the Low-Literacy Newspaper Really a Newspaper? (Box 391)
    - Leidenfrost, Theodore A Ladder of Literacy for the Kpelle People of Liberia (Box 391)
    - Lichtman, Gail Shaw
      - Survey of Former Students (Box 391)
      - The Political Aspects of Language (Box 391)
    - Light (Box 449)
    - Likely, Diana / A Ladder of Literacy for American Indians (Box 391)
    - Magney, Gordon
      - The Expressed Reading Interests and Motivations of Male Literacy Students in Kabul (Box 425)
      - A Literacy Manual for Afghanistan (Box 391)
      - Teaching Literacy by Radio in Developing Countries (Box 391)
    - Magney, Gordon & Grace
      - Akbar Conquers His Sickness (Box 391)
      - Literacy in Afghanistan (Box 391)
    - Magney, Grace
      - A Ladder of Literacy for Women of Afghanistan (Box 391)
      - The Paper Crunch (Box 391)
    - Magsanoc, Maria
      - The New Streamlined English Series (Box 391)
      - An Organization Image Profile of Laubach Literacy Inc. in the Syracuse Community (Box 330)
    - Mando, Bonnie Brennan / Tutoring Log (Box 391)
    - Marsick, Victoria / Literacy and Family Planning in India (Box 391)
    - Melling, Carol / Ladder of Literacy for Syracuse State School (Box 391)
    - Melton, Richard / Effects on overt behavior of alternative mass communication persuasion, "Strategies: a controlled field experiment," Syracuse University Ph.D., 1969; 2 folders (Box 449)
    - Mgbemena, Nwabu / The Population of New Readers (Nigeria) (Box 391)
    - Mucorlor, Roland / Priorities for Adult Literacy (Box 391)
    - Mundukzhy, Thomas / Content Analysis of "The Orthodox Church," a Monthly Newspaper (Box 391)
    - Nayana; Newspaper for New Literates (India), 1964 (Box 449)
    - Nichols, Marcia / Illiteracy in Haiti (Box 391)
    - One Step Forward (Box 449)
    - Otoo, Samuel Koff and Felix Seth Konu / Experiment in readability, 1957 (Box 449)
    - Patrick, Marj / First United Methodist Church of Syracuse: 150 Years of Ministry in Syracuse (plus booklet) (Box 391)
    - Patterson, Ronald Paul / Basic Literacy Books (Box 392)
    - Piepgrass, Marci Nichols / Illiteracy in Haiti (Box 392)
    - Raines, Nancy
      - Educational Problems of Chinese Americans (Box 392)
      - Illiteracy Among Chinese in the U.S (Box 392)
      - Ladder of Literacy for Chinese Children (San Francisco) (Box 392)
      - Literacy: Lighting Up Lives (Box 392)
    - Read and Grow, vol. 1 no. 1 (Box 449)
    - Renteria, Ana Maria de Himno / Laubach (Box 392)
    - Roberts, Helen
      - How to Write a Play (Box 392)
      - In the Beginning (Box 392)
    - Rosario, Florangel Z.
      - A Ladder of Literacy for a Philippine Province (Box 392)
      - Mass Communications Research in Asia (Box 392)
    - Rose, Linda / Church Public Relations: Three Syracuse Catholic Churches (Box 392)
    - Runbeck, Margaret Lee / Anand the Wise Man v. 1 & 2 (Box 392)
    - Sawyer, Diane J. / Diagnostic inventory (Box 449)
    - Schock, Mary Ellen
      - Descriptive Analysis of the Adult Literacy Primer Leamos y Escribamos (Box 392)
      - Functions of Linguistic Elements in Primer Construction (Box 392)
      - Linguistics and Literacy (Box 392)
    - Schroeder, Dennis / A Literacy Experiment in Africa (Box 393)
    - Scofield, Willard
      - A Ladder of Literacy for Bandundu, Zaire (Box 393)
      - Literacy Book Reviews (Box 393)
      - Prospectus: Revision of Primer in Kituba (Box 393)
    - Shelley, Geraldine C./ A Survey: What Do New Literates Want to Read? (Box 393)
    - Shipstone, Norah / Four Readability Formulas: A Comparison (Box 393)
    - Small, Mary Luins / For Our Literacy Gap: The Laubach Connection? (Box 393)
    - Smalley, Margaret Adult / Illiteracy in Indianapolis (Box 393)
    - Smith, Peter E. / Motivating Teachers and Students (Box 393)
    - Snowman, Margaret / Adult Learning and Motivation (Box 393)
    - Snyder, Craig / Testing Short Stories on Poor Readers in Syracuse Schools (Box 393)
    - Sola, Donald / Quechua Language Program at Cornell University (Box 393)
    - Spillberg, Ruth / Finding a Job in Syracuse (Box 393)
    - Stamps, Stanley D. / Illiterates: Resources for Help (Box 393)